<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed172.atom</id>
  <title>Marquee de Sells</title>
  <updated>2019-08-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
  <link rel="first" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/feed.atom"/>
  <link rel="last" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed178.atom"/>
  <link rel="previous" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed171.atom"/>
  <link rel="next" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed173.atom"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed172.atom"/>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Sells</name>
    <uri>https://csells.github.io/sb6/</uri>
    <email>csells@sellsbrothers.com</email>
  </author>
  <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
  <category term="book" label="Books"/>
  <category term="books" label="Books"/>
  <category term="colophon" label="Colophon"/>
  <category term="conference" label="Conference"/>
  <category term="data" label="Data"/>
  <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
  <category term="interview" label="Interviewing"/>
  <category term="money" label="Money"/>
  <category term="oslofeaturedcontent" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="osloeditorial" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="oslo" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="telerik" label="Telerik"/>
  <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
  <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
  <category term="win8" label="Windows 8"/>
  <category term="writing" label="Writing"/>
  <icon>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/images/vikingme128x128.jpg</logo>
  <subtitle>Chris's insight outlet</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12661</id>
    <title>Welcome to Wahoo!</title>
    <updated>2002-01-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" href="/public/wahoo/wahoo.JPG"/>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2002-01-15T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>This page is dedicated to the game of Wahoo! -- a.NET application meant to be invoked from a.NET client across the internet. If you'd like the ClickOnce version (for.NET 2.0), click here and (after clicking a few more times), an application that looks like the picture on the right will appear. To invoke the No-Touch Version version (for.NET 1.x), click here and wait a little while. In a few seconds, an application that looks like the picture on the right will appear. You should note that No-Touch Deployed a...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Welcome to Wahoo!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/public/wahoo2/Wahoo.application">
&lt;img border="0" src="/public/wahoo/wahoo.JPG" align="right" hspace="10" width="281" height="590">&lt;/a>This page is dedicated to the game of Wahoo! 
-- a .NET application meant to be 
invoked from a .NET client across the internet. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you'd like the ClickOnce version (for .NET 2.0),
&lt;a href="/public/wahoo2/Wahoo.application">click here&lt;/a> and (after clicking a few 
more times), an application that looks like the picture on the right will 
appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To invoke the No-Touch Version version (for .NET 1.x),
&lt;a href="/public/wahoo/wahoo.exe">click here&lt;/a> and wait a little while. In a few seconds, 
an application that looks like the picture on the right will appear. &lt;i>You 
should note that No-Touch Deployed applications deployed across the Internet are 
disabled by default when .NET 2.0 is installed on the client machine.&lt;/i>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you find that Wahoo! doesn't have permission to run on your .NET 1.x computer, you 
can &lt;a href="/public/wahoo/WahooPermissionsSetup.msi">grant Wahoo! Internet permissions using 
this MSI setup file&lt;/a> (Keith Brown helped me fix my SP1 permissions problem!). Even the new permissions are pretty strict, e.g. they do not 
even allow writing to the file system. If you'd like to increase the permissions 
allows for Wahoo! so that it can cache high scores to the file system, you can 
do so via the Trust Assembly Wizard available in Start-&amp;gt;Settings-&amp;gt;Control 
Panel-&amp;gt;Administration Tools-&amp;gt;Microsoft .NET Framework Wizards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font color="#FF0000">&lt;b>Keith Brown has asked me to remind all of you that 
even though Wahoo! is managed and executes in the .NET security sandbox, the 
code in the MSI to grant permissions for the .NET 1.0x version is running with FullTrust permissions, meaning that it could do 
bad things, where &amp;quot;bad things&amp;quot; is defined as: trash the registry, delete files, 
send email from your account, spread viruses, reformat disks, change arbitrary 
spreadsheet values or formulae, remove single columns from database tables, 
invert the buttons on your mouse, reset your MineSweeper high scores, send lists 
of installed software to Microsoft, and generally misbehave (thanks Tim Ewald 
for the exhaustive list : ). Of course, this applies to any MSI file, setup 
program or any other code that you download onto your machine and run outside of 
the .NET or Win32 security sandboxes. Keith would like everyone to promise to 
stop installing new code of any kind on their machines and let software migrate 
there instead, either via No-Touch Deployment/mobile code-style install-on-demand or via 
administrator-approved means. Keith believes that installing code on your 
machine can only cause trouble and I agree -- unless there is code on your 
machine, nothing bad can happen. Nothing good can happen, either, but &amp;quot;Hey, 
let's be careful out there!&amp;quot;&lt;/b>&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> 
&lt;a href="/public/writing/wfbook">The full source code to the .NET 2.0 version is 
available here&lt;/a>. 
&lt;a href="/public/wahoo/Wahoo.zip">The full source code to the .NET 1.x version (including the MSI file) is available here&lt;/a>. The
&lt;a href="/public/wahoo/html/index.htm">original HTML version&lt;/a> is available, as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wahoo! was awarded 
&lt;a href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/team/windowsforms/WindowsFormsCodingHero2_12_02.aspx">the Windows Forms Coding Heroes Award&lt;/a> on 2/12/02 
by the Windows Forms team on GotDotNet. I'd like to thank the academy... : )&lt;/p>

&lt;p>If you like this game, you might also like
&lt;a href="http://www.valuediscovery.com/snake.exe">Snake&lt;/a>, by
&lt;a href="mailto:tomasg@SPSS.COM">Tomas Gudmundsson&lt;/a>. I know I do.&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12366</id>
    <title>The Game of Wahoo!</title>
    <updated>2002-01-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2002-01-15T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>If you like Tetris and you've got.NET installed, check out Wahoo. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>The Game of Wahoo!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you like Tetris and you've got &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/downloads/default.asp?url=/downloads/sample.asp?url=/MSDN-FILES/027/001/829/msdncompositedoc.xml">.NET installed&lt;/a>, check out &lt;a href="/public/wahoo/">Wahoo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12429</id>
    <title>VS.NET Fun Facts</title>
    <updated>2002-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
    <published>2002-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>If you haven't seen it yet, check out the VS.NET Fun Facts piece that started as praise and bitching about VS.NET, but turned into something pretty useful if you'd like to get the most out of VS.NET. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>VS.NET Fun Facts&lt;/h1>

    &lt;p>If you haven't seen it yet, check out the
    &lt;a href="/12594">VS.NET Fun Facts piece&lt;/a> that started 
    as praise and bitching about VS.NET, but turned into something pretty useful 
    if you'd like to get the most out of VS.NET.&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12594</id>
    <title>VS.NET Fun Facts</title>
    <updated>2002-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-01-06T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>After about a month of banging my head on it, Visual Studio.NET has become my favorite IDE of all time. To save you the bruising, I thought I'd post some productivity tricks and traps I've learned [1] that make VS.NET useful. If you've got your own, send them to me and I'll post the good ones. DISCLAIMER: I always leave the standard VS.NET key bindings, i.e. I don't set it to VC6 style. In general, I just learn the default keystrokes for things instead of changing them. Saves me time when repaving my machin...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>VS.NET Fun Facts&lt;/h1>
        &lt;p>After about a month of banging my head on it, Visual Studio.NET has 
        become my favorite IDE of all time. To save you the bruising, I 
        thought I'd post some productivity tricks and traps I've learned [1] that 
        make VS.NET useful. If you've got your own,
        &lt;a href="mailto:csells@sellsbrothers.com?subject=Here's a VS.NET Fun Fact for you!">
        send them to me&lt;/a> and I'll post the good ones.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>&lt;b>DISCLAIMER: &lt;/b>I always leave the standard VS.NET key bindings, i.e. I 
        don't set it to VC6 style. In general, I just learn the default 
        keystrokes for things instead of changing them. Saves me time when 
        repaving my machines or sitting down at strange machines. If you've 
        changed key bindings in your VS.NET, these keystrokes aren't likely to 
        work, but the tricks will still be useful if you can figure out what the 
        key bindings are.&lt;/p>
        &lt;h2>Download&lt;/h2>
        &lt;p>If you don't already have VS.NET, run, don't walk, to MSDN to 
        download a
        &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/productinfo/trial.asp">
        60-day evaluation of VS.NET Professional&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
        &lt;h2>Tricks&lt;/h2>
        &lt;ul>
          &lt;li>The most important thing I've done to make VS.NET useful for me is 
          to &lt;b>unpin all of the windows&lt;/b>. This gives me tons of room for the source 
          or design view. This, combined with the keystrokes to pull out 
          the windows (below) as I need them, is probably my favorite feature of VS.NET.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>The 2nd most important thing to know is that VS.NET can be invoked 
          from Start-&amp;gt;Run using its name &amp;quot;devenv&amp;quot; (no quotes). Therefore, 
          &lt;b>to 
          start VS.NET, type Ctrl-Esc, R, devenv, Enter&lt;/b>. Much better than 
          digging into the deep Programs menu.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Make sure to &lt;b>move the &amp;quot;Visual Studio .NET Command Prompt&amp;quot;&lt;/b> that's 
          buried deep inside of Start-&amp;gt;Programs-&amp;gt;Microsoft Visual Studio 
          .NET-&amp;gt;Visual Studio .NET Tools to somewhere more handy, e.g. the Quick 
          Launch toolbar, so that you can get to it easily. You'll be using the 
          command shell often in your .NET development.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>Let the IDE implement the stubs of an interface function in a 
          class&lt;/b> (not a struct):&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>Type the name of the interface after the name of the class, e.g. 
            &amp;quot;class Foo : IDisposable&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>In the Class View (Ctrl-Shift-C), navigate to the class, e.g. 
            Foo, and choose the interface you'd like stubs for under Bases and 
            Interfaces for that class.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>In the context menu (Shift-F10), choose Add-&amp;gt;Implement 
            Interface.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Bask in the glory of
            &lt;a href="http://www.donbox.com/">Don Box&lt;/a> (who 
            showed me this trick).&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>Let the IDE implement the stub of an virtual function override&lt;/b>:&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>In the Class View (Ctrl-Shift-C), navigate to the class, e.g. 
            Foo, and choose the method on the base class you'd like to override 
            under Bases and 
            Interfaces for that class.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>In the context menu (Shift-F10), choose Add-&amp;gt;Override.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Bask in the glory of me, who found this all by myself. I found 
            this digging through the .VSZ files on my system. It looks like you 
            can add your own context items to the menus, which sounds like 
            fun...&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>If you'd like some samples of VS.NET Add-Ins,
          &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/nextgen/automation.asp">
          MS provides some&lt;/a>. MSDN Magazine provides
          &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/msdnmag/issues/02/02/VSIDE/VSIDE.asp">
          an add-in article&lt;/a> that you may find useful.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Likewise, &lt;span class="pd">&lt;a href="mailto:leon@exmsft.com">Leo A. 
          Notenboom&lt;/a> has written
          &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/msdnmag/issues/02/02/VSIDE/VSIDE.asp">
          a thorough article about how to write an add-in to VS.NET&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;span class="pd">Also, in &lt;/span>
            &lt;a href="http://www.codeproject.com/netcomponents/propertytree.asp">A Designable 
                PropertyTree for VS.NET&lt;/a>: &lt;a href="mailto:rmorris@cc.gatech.edu">Russell 
                Morris&lt;/a>
        has built an implementation of the PropertyTree control that you see in 
        VS.NET's Project Properties dialog. What makes this really cool is that 
        Russell's control is a great example of what to do to integrate with the VS.NET 
        Forms Designer. &lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>If you'd like to &lt;b>add to the Solution, Project, Project Item or 
          Context Menu wizards&lt;/b> for VC++, VC# or VB.NET, you can. Here's
          &lt;a href="/public/writing/projectItemTemplates.htm">
          an example of a project item wizard that produces a custom aspx file 
          and a custom code behind file to go with it&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>While ildasm.exe is very thorough, if you'd like to have &lt;b>a 
          prettier view of the types in an assembly, you can load it into the 
          VS.NET Object Browser&lt;/b>. Using the file open dialog, click the 
          drop-down and choose Open With and select the Object Browser. Once 
          it's loaded, you can unload it by choosing the Remove item from the 
          context menu of the assembly in the Object Browser.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>This isn't a tip so much as an observation. If you use an #if with 
          a compilation symbol, e.g. DEBUG or TRACE, notice that as you move 
          from configuration to configuration that the editor will gray out the 
          code path that won't be taken. Is that cool, or what?!?&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>Read the online documentation. &lt;/b>It's *so* much more useful than the 
          online documentation of old.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li> &lt;a href="mailto:ballen@DEVELOP.COM">Brock Allen&lt;/a> showed me &lt;b>the 
          3rd tab (Projects) in the Add References dialog&lt;/b> for adding references 
          from one project to the target of another. This works *so* much better 
          than hard-coding .NET references to a specific output folder.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:elstegman@home.com">Ed Stegman&lt;/a> pointed out 
          that &lt;b>the Toolbox can be used to store snippets of code&lt;/b>. Simply select 
          some and drag-n-drop it on the Toolbox. To paste, drag-n-drop from the 
          Toolbox to your editor. Of course, this is great for duplicating bugs 
          as well. : )&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Ed really likes &lt;b>regions&lt;/b>, marked using #region/#endregion compiler 
          directives, too. Now that's he's clued me into the keystrokes (below) 
          for expanding and collapsing them, I really like them, too. : )&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Ed also reminded me of &lt;b>the Task List&lt;/b> and how anything marked with TODO, HACK or UNDONE will be included in your list of tasks.
          &lt;a href="mailto:Astopford@beta.dabs.com">Andrew Stopford&lt;/a> reminded 
          me that you can set up your own keywords via Tools -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; 
          Environment.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>If, on the other hand, you &lt;b>hate the Task List&lt;/b>,
          &lt;a href="mailto:kperry@microsoft.com">Kevin Perry&lt;/a> suggested the 
          followings steps to turn if off after a build:&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>Go to Tools -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; Environment -&amp;gt; Project and Solutions.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Uncheck the &amp;quot;Show task list window if build finishes with 
            errors&amp;quot; option.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Make sure the &amp;quot;Show output window when build starts&amp;quot; option is 
            checked.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Now go and close the task list window and it's gone for good!&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Several folks have sent along &lt;b>macros that are life savers&lt;/b> to them.
          &lt;a href="mailto:csells@sellsbrothers.com?subject=A VS.NET Macro To Die For!">
          If you'd like to do that&lt;/a>, I'm happy to post them here along with 
          your name and a brief description. Please send attached files instead 
          of inline text, however. Thanks!&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:richard.broida@datatraknet.com">Richard Broida&lt;/a> 
          sent along &lt;b> &lt;a href="/public/spout/KeyboardShortcuts.zip">a macro that inserts curly 
          braces&lt;/a>&lt;/b> and moves insertion point to first line inside, following 
          K&amp;amp;R or MS style, depending on indentation option.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:jcauble@caublestoneink.com">Joshua Cauble&lt;/a> sent 
          along &lt;b> &lt;a href="/public/spout/IDEEnhancements.zip">a macro to sort declarations in a 
          VB.NET&lt;/a>&lt;/b> class to get the items in the wizard bar sorted.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Don Box sent along a &lt;b>&lt;a href="/public/spout/emacsCompileMacro.txt">macro to achieve emacs-like M-x compile functionality&lt;/a>&lt;/b>.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:pan@interse.com">Peter Andersen&lt;/a> sent in &lt;b>
          &lt;a href="/public/spout/PanModule.zip">a macro that creates a C# string from an 
          arbitrary mark&lt;/a>&lt;/b>, e.g.. if you select the following lines:&lt;br>
          &lt;br>
          &amp;lt;xml&amp;gt;&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;lt;hithere&amp;gt;mom&amp;lt;/hithere&amp;gt;&lt;br>
          &amp;lt;/xml&amp;gt;&lt;br>
          &lt;br>
          running the macro produces the following output in the editor:&lt;br>
          &lt;br>
          &amp;quot;&amp;lt;xml&amp;gt;&amp;quot; +&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;hithere&amp;gt;mom&amp;lt;/hithere&amp;gt;&amp;quot;+&lt;br>
          &amp;quot;&amp;lt;/xml&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:drub0y@hotmail.com">Drew Marsh&lt;/a> 
          pointed out that &lt;b>Ctrl-S works in any of the output windows&lt;/b>, 
          e.g. build, debug, etc, to save the contents to a file.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">It's cool to have MS folk reading this list.
          &lt;a href="mailto:kperry@microsoft.com">Kevin Perry&lt;/a> sent me to 
          procedure to bypass the &amp;quot;Attach to Process&amp;quot; dialog that asks what kind 
          of debugger you'd like to pick, i.e. CLR, T-SQL, Native and/or Script, 
          when you click on the Attach... button in the Debug Processes dialog. 
          &lt;b>Ctrl-clicking on Attach... will give you the Native debugger without 
          asking.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b>&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">My good friend &lt;a href="mailto:tewald@obelisk-llc.com">
          Tim Ewald&lt;/a> reminded me that one of the coolest features of VS.NET 
          is that the solution explorer is really just a view of your actual 
          project folders in the shell. This is especially useful if you choose 
          Show All Files, so that you can add files to your project that are 
          already in your project directory simply by using the context menu. If 
          you'd like &lt;b>to add a file that isn't in your project, you can do so 
          by opening the file and choosing &amp;quot;Move &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; into Project&amp;quot; from the 
          context menu&lt;/b>. This is a poorly named item, however, as it actually 
          links to the existing file outside the project instead of moving it in 
          the file system (although the linking is the correct behavior).&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">To &lt;b>speed the IDE start-up time&lt;/b>, you want to 
          avoid the browser being loaded. To do that, from the Start Page, 
          choose My Profile and set At Startup to Show empty environment. Also, 
          close the Dynamic Help window and the Start Page. Now IE will only be 
          loaded on demand.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">If you like the tabs showing the various files you 
          have open, but miss &lt;b>the ability to show multiple files at the same 
          time&lt;/b>, right-click on one of the tabs and choose New 
          Horizontal/Vertical Tab Group. Both tab groups will show 
          simultaneously and you can move tabs (and therefore the window that 
          the tab represents) between tab groups by right-clicking on the tab.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:m_cabreu@hotmail.com">Maria Abreu&lt;/a> 
          points out that VS.NET, by default, neglects to colorize strings (an 
          omission, IMO). You can colorize them via Tools-&amp;gt;Options-&amp;gt;Fonts and 
          Colors and it really helps. Thanks, Maria.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;span id="MSGHDR-PRE">&lt;span id="MSGHDR-FROM-PRE">
          &lt;a href="mailto:graeme.foster@ASTON.TV">Graeme Foster&lt;/a> posted
          &lt;a href="http://discuss.develop.com/archives/wa.exe?A2=ind0201B&amp;L=DOTNET&amp;P=R27347">
          this tip on the DOTNET mailing list&lt;/a> for &lt;/span>
          &lt;span id="MSGHDR-SUBJECT-PRE">&lt;b>getting VS.NET to copy the 
          application .config file during the build&lt;/b>: simply name the file 
          app.config and put it in the main project directory. At build time, 
          VS.NET will copy the file into the output directory with the build 
          output.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:db@die-lounge.com">Dominick Baier&lt;/a> 
          reminded me that by &lt;b>typing &amp;quot;///&amp;quot; (no quotes) above the declaration 
          of a method or property, the C# editor will give you the template for 
          the C# XML documentation tags&lt;/b> with all parameters and return 
          value. The IDE will compose these comments into (fairly ugly) 
          HTML-based documentation for your classes using the Tools-&amp;gt;Build 
          Comment Web Pages menu item. A much nicer set of documentation from 
          these comments can be generated by
          &lt;a href="http://ndoc.sourceforge.net/">NDoc&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:studyonnet@hotmail.com">Kunal Cheda&lt;/a> 
          pointed out that if you've got multiple things you'd like to start 
          when running or debugging a solution, you can do so at Solution 
          Explorer-&amp;gt;Solution Properties-&amp;gt;Startup Project-&amp;gt;Multiple Startup 
          Projects. *Very* handy for client-server testing.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:nickhod@microsoft.com">Nick Hodapp&lt;/a> 
          passed along this tip on how to &lt;b>exclude included files that don't 
          change from VC++ dependency checking:&lt;/b>&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Add header file directory names (using full, absolute 
          paths) one per line, to SYSINCL.dat.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Exit the development environment.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Restart the development environment.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Click Rebuild for changes to take effect, noticing a 
          reduction in build times.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:shawnv@arithex.com">Shawn Van Ness&lt;/a> 
          thinks that &lt;b>the clipboard ring &amp;quot;is so cool, it should be 
          back-propped into all of Windows&amp;quot;&lt;/b>: Using Ctrl+Shift+V as an 
          alternative to the usual Ctrl+V paste command, will &amp;quot;cycle&amp;quot; through 
          the last dozen or so bits of text you've copied onto the clipboard. 
          This simple user scenario demonstrates:&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Copy &amp;quot;#if DEBUG&amp;quot; onto the clipboard.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">A few lines below, copy &amp;quot;#else&amp;quot; onto the clipboard.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">A few lines further below, copy &amp;quot;#endif&amp;quot; onto the 
          clipboard.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Scroll down many hundreds of lines... or open a 
          different file, etc.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Ctrl+Shift+V to paste &amp;quot;#endif&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Ctrl+Shift+V, Ctrl+Shift+V to paste &amp;quot;#else&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Ctrl+Shift+V, Ctrl+Shift+V, Ctrl+Shift+V to paste &amp;quot;#if 
          DEBUG&amp;quot;.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:Scott@Corillian.com">Scott Hanselman&lt;/a> 
          pointed out that you can set the font size to VS.NET from the command 
          line using the /fs argument, e.g. &amp;quot;devenv.exe /fs 14&amp;quot;. This is great 
          for presenters!&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">For &lt;b>the complete list of key bindings&lt;/b>, MS 
          provides
          &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/code/default.asp?URL=/code/sample.asp?url=/msdn-files/026/002/527/msdncompositedoc.xml">
          a Keybindings Table Add-In&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="/public/spout/KeyMap.zip">Here it is 
          already compiled&lt;/a>. Just drop it anywhere, register it as a COM 
          server and the next time you start VS, you'll have a KeyMap command in 
          the Help menu.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:russell@synthesystems.com">Russell 
          Sinclair&lt;/a> has provided &lt;a href="/public/spout/rsvskeys.xls">his favorite key 
          bindings in an Excel spreadsheet&lt;/a> that prints and folds nicely for 
          keeping it handy.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Here are &lt;b>my favorite key bindings&lt;/b>:&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" id="AutoNumber1" style="border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top: 1.5pt solid black; border-bottom: 1.5pt solid black; background-color: white" fpstyle="26,111111000">
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: bold; color: navy; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: 1.5pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Keys&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: bold; color: navy; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: 1.5pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Binding&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              F8/Shift-F8&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Navigate compilation errors&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-D&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Move to mini-buffer&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Shift-G in mini-buffer or&lt;br>
              Ctrl-O in mini-buffer&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open file name in mini-buffer (Ctrl-O seems to open stuff 
              Ctrl-Shift-G does not)&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              &amp;quot;&amp;gt; command&amp;quot; in mini-buffer&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Execute command&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl+/&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Move to mini-buffer, typing the leading &amp;gt; for you&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Alt-A&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open the command window&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-PageUp in HTML Design View&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open source view&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">Ctrl-PageDown 
              in HTML Source View&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open design view&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              F7 in Form Design View&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open source view&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Shift-F7 in Form Source View&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Open design view&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Alt-L&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Solution Explorer&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">F4 
              or Alt-Enter&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Properties of selected item&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Shift-B&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Build&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              F5&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Debug&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-F5&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Run, but not debug&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Alt-J&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Object Browser&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Shift-C&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Class View&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Space when typing a symbol&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Complete the symbol you're currently typing or give you a choice 
              of possibilities&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Space when entering arguments&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Show the function prototype&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; (no quotes) as the name of a menu item&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Menu item becomes a separator&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-K Ctrl-F&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Reformat selection&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              }&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Reformat scope being closed&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-K Ctrl-C&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Comment out selected lines&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-K Ctrl-U&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Uncomment selected lines&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-}&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Match braces, brackets or compiler directives&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Shift-Ctrl-}&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Select match between braces, brackets or compiler directives&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-L or Shift-Del or&lt;br>
              Ctrl-X w/ no selection&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Delete entire line&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Del&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Delete next &amp;quot;word&amp;quot;&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Alt-F6&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Next visible pane (not for use with all windows unpinned)&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-Shift-F12&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Jumps to next *whatever*, depending on what's active, e.g. next 
              find result, next task, next error, etc.&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;/Ctrl-Shift-&amp;quot;-&amp;quot; (no quotes)&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Jumps to last/next place you worked&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-C in the Class View&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Copies fully qualified name to the Clipboard&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-M Ctrl-M&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Collapse or expand a region or outlined block (as marked by the 
              [+] and [-] on the left hand side of the editor).&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-M Ctrl-O&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Collapse everything in the current file&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-M Ctrl-L&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Expand everything in the current file&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              F12&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Jump to the current symbol's declaration&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-G, line #, Enter or&lt;br>
              Ctrl-D, line #, Ctrl-G&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Jump to line&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-I/Ctrl-Shift-I + string&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Incremental search for string&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl-R+Ctrl-R&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Turn on/off word wrap&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Ctrl+Up/Down Arrow&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Scroll window up/down without moving the cursor away from the 
              current line&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
            &lt;tr>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Shift+Alt+Arrows&lt;br>
              (Alt+Mouse works, too)&lt;/td>
              &lt;td style="font-weight: normal; color: black; border-left-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-bottom: .75pt solid black; background-color: white" align="left" valign="top">
              Column selection (include of line selection)&lt;/td>
            &lt;/tr>
          &lt;/table>
          &lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
        &lt;h2>Traps&lt;/h2>
        &lt;ul>
          &lt;li>VS.NET's Copy Project uses FrontPage Extensions to publish a web 
          site from a local testing machine to the deployment machine. This is 
          virtually important if you don't want to hack on your live web sites. However, 
          &lt;b>Copy Project sends everything every time instead of sending the deltas&lt;/b>, so it's 
          pretty worthless as far as I can tell. Instead,
          &lt;a href="http://www.quality.nu/">Brad Wilson&lt;/a> clued 
          me into the FrontPage Publish Web command, which only publishes 
          deltas.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>The command window (or &amp;gt; in the mini-buffer) seems really cool&lt;/b>, 
          but I don't know any good commands to type.
          &lt;a href="mailto:csells@sellsbrothers.com?subject=Here's a cool VS.NET command!">
          Do you?&lt;/a>&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:Joe.Bauer@PRICESystems.com">Joe Bauer&lt;/a> points 
          out that you can, of course, use the command window to print fields or 
          call methods using the ?, e.g. &amp;quot;&amp;gt; ? objMyClass.GetCount()&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:rbirkby@thundermain.com">Richard Birkby&lt;/a> 
          pointed out the &amp;quot;shell&amp;quot; command, which seems a bit unwieldy for me, 
          but you may like it. &amp;quot;&amp;gt;shell /?&amp;quot; in the mini-buffer will show usage 
          (now that's cool!).&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:dmarsh@mimeo.com">Drew Marsh&lt;/a> points out that 
          the command window (or the mini-buffer with a &amp;gt; prefix) allows you to 
          execute any command provided by the shell, add-ins, or macros. 
          Anything you don't bind to a key combination or toolbar button, you 
          can go into the command window to execute. Also, it supports 
          auto-completion for those of us with poor memories.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:richard.broida@datatraknet.com">Richard Broida&lt;/a> 
          pointed out the use of the &amp;quot;?&amp;quot; command to print variables at debug 
          time.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:jlam@IUNKNOWN.COM">John Lam&lt;/a> showed me where
          &lt;a href="ms-help://MS.VSCC/MS.MSDNVS/vsintro7/html/vxgrfpredefinedcommandlinealiases.htm">
          the docs are for the pre-defined command aliases&lt;/a>. He also points 
          out that you can create your own aliases, but you need cool commands 
          first before you can do that. : )&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&lt;a href="mailto:ramakrishnavavilala@3csoftware.com">
          Ramakrishna Vavilala&lt;/a> recommends a cool alias &amp;quot;&amp;gt;alias ! shell 
          /command cmd /c&amp;quot; which reduces the syntax of the shell command 
          considerably and sends the command output to the Command window.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">Don Box pointed me at two commands that forces me to 
          learn the keyboard shortcut to put focus in the command window 
          (Ctrl-Alt-A):&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&amp;quot;&amp;gt;open &amp;lt;partial path&amp;gt;&amp;quot; will give Intellisense on the 
          file system, e.g. &amp;quot;&amp;gt;open c:\&amp;quot;.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>
          &lt;p align="left">&amp;quot;&amp;gt;File.NewFile &amp;lt;file name&amp;gt;&amp;quot; will open a new file with 
          the appropriate name and syntax highlighting, e.g. &amp;quot;&amp;gt;open foo.cs&amp;quot;. 
          This is even handier when you alias &amp;quot;new&amp;quot; to File.NewFile, e.g. 
          &amp;quot;&amp;gt;alias new File.NewFile&amp;quot;, because you can just do this &amp;quot;&amp;gt;new foo.cs&amp;quot;.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>As far as I can tell, &lt;b>there is no way in a C# project to run 
          custom pre or post-build commands&lt;/b>, either on a project or a file 
          level. If the VC++ wizards still had a Utility project, that could be 
          used, but the closest I've seen in VS.NET is a Makefile project. 
          Anyone have ideas on this one?&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>Several folks have recommended
          &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/code/default.asp?URL=/code/sample.asp?url=/msdn-files/026/002/526/msdncompositedoc.xml">
          a VS.NET Add-In Sample that is supposed to provide this capability&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:kperry@microsoft.com">Kevin Perry&lt;/a> showed me 
          where the UI scrambler put the Utility project in this version of the 
          IDE:&lt;ol>
            &lt;li>Run the makefile appwizard to create a makefile project.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Bring up the project properties for the project and look at the 
            general page&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Select Utility in the Configuration Type property drop down.&lt;/li>
            &lt;li>Click Apply.&lt;br>
            POOF! Instant Utility project.&lt;br>
            BTW: C++ Static Library projects can also double as utility projects 
            in a pinch.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;/ol>
          &lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>As cute as the Add Reference menu item is on a project's context 
          menu, your going to have to &lt;b>avoid Add Reference for COM servers&lt;/b> and build the 
          references by hand if you sign your assemblies (which you should 
          always do). Apparently a signed assembly is not allowed to reference 
          an assembly that's not signed and the Add Reference menu item doesn't 
          sign the generated assembly. All Add Reference does is the moral 
          equivalent of the tlbimp command line tool anyway, so get used to 
          calling it yourself using the /keyfile command line argument. If you 
          import COM Controls, e.g. the WebBrowser control, you'll 
          need to use aximp instead of tlbimp, but the /keyfile argument is the 
          same.&lt;br>
          &lt;br>
          However, &lt;a href="mailto:jerry@dennany.org">Jerry Dennany&lt;/a> points 
          out that you can have VS.NET itself sign your interop assemblies by 
          going to the Project Properties, and under Common Properties / General 
          there will be a section for &amp;quot;wrapper Assembly for ActiveX / COM 
          Objects.&amp;quot; You may place your path to the Key File here, and everything 
          still works from the IDE.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>There are no wizards for standard SDI, MDI or Explorer-style 
          applications in WinForms&lt;/b> as there were in VC++ for MFC applications. 
          However, the wizard stuff is there, although it's obscure, so maybe I'll build one. 
          I've certainly done my share of that kind of 
          work...&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Likewise, there is no built in support for MFC-style document 
          handling, separation of data and view, command line processing or 
          command UI handling. I've done my share of &lt;a href="/12652">
          that kind of work&lt;/a>, too, and I *will* be building that stuff. 
          Anyone want to
          &lt;a href="mailto:csells@sellsbrothers.com?subject=I'd love to help add MFC-style functionality to .NET!">
          volunteer to help&lt;/a>?&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>I don't seem to be able to &lt;b>get a custom control on the toolbox&lt;/b> 
          unless it's part of a separate assembly. What if I have a custom 
          control in my application? Can I make it show up on the toolbox 
          somehow?&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:bobb@develop.com">Bob Beauchemin&lt;/a> pointed out 
          that I can customize the toolbox and point it at a built version of my 
          EXE, which sounds kind of awkward, but works.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>I can't tell. &lt;b>Is everything being recompiled every time I build&lt;/b>, 
          regardless of whether the source has changed or not?&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>Drew Marsh pointed out that the Incremental Build option in a C# 
          project will decide whether you rebuild only if it is changed or not.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>If a file is &amp;quot;thought of&amp;quot; internally by the IDE as one text, e.g. 
          Text, and you try to save it as another type, e.g. XML, &lt;b>if you're not 
          very careful the save 
          dialog will append the extension of the type it thinks it is&lt;/b>, e.g. 
          .txt. To enforce the extension you want, put double quotes around the file 
          name, e.g. &amp;quot;foo.xml&amp;quot;.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>Neither BeginInvoke nor EndInvoke is shown when calling methods on 
          a delegate in C#&lt;/b>, even though they do in VB.NET. This just seems 
          wrong...&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>Docs on the built-in VsWizardEngine that VS.NET provides would be 
          nice.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul>
          &lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:jfland@develop.com">Jon Flanders&lt;/a> says that 
          they're documented as part of Enterprise Templates.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
          &lt;/li>
          &lt;li>By default, &lt;b>adding a new project to an existing solution wants to 
          put the new project in a peer directory instead of in a sub-directory&lt;/b>. 
          This seems strange if you're trying to keep these things together 
          (which, presumably, you are if you're grouping multiple projects into 
          a single solution). Certainly, I've seen users dig through several 
          peer directories looking for the solution file. I put sub-projects 
          into sub-directories by hand, but it would be nice if the IDE did this 
          automatically.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>Cleaning a project of it's output files doesn't actually work for 
          C# or VB.NET projects&lt;/b> (although the UI shows it as an option, as does 
          the command line). &lt;a href="mailto:tomasr@mvps.org">Tomas Restrepo&lt;/a> 
          has provided &lt;b>
          &lt;a href="http://www.mvps.org/windev/dotnet/ProjectCleaner.html">
          an add-in that provides the missing Clean functionality&lt;/a>&lt;/b>, along 
          with a rant on what problems he had building the add-in.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>In spite of CodeWright and every other 3rd party editor supporting 
          it for years, &lt;b>VS still doesn't support keyword expansion&lt;/b>, e.g. 
          expanding &amp;quot;if( &amp;quot; into &amp;quot;if( | )\n{\n}&amp;quot;, so I use
          &lt;a href="http://www.nilgirihouse.com/">Dexter, from 
          NilgiriHouse&lt;/a>. I don't have to change my typing habits at all, but 
          I get tons o' text for free.&lt;br>
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li>
          &lt;li>&lt;b>The macro recorder is pretty stunted&lt;/b>. For example, if I 
          want a macro to switch between some editor settings, e.g. my normal 
          code formatting style and my prose code formatting style, and I record 
          a macro to watch me change the settings, all the recorded macro does 
          is record that the dialog was shown, not what settings I changed. What 
          a let down...&lt;/li>
        &lt;/ul>
        &lt;p>&lt;i>[1] I've learned a ton of these tricks and traps from my fellow 
        DevelopMentor instructors, my students and the
        &lt;a href="http://discuss.develop.com/">.NET mailing list&lt;/a>, 
        all of which I can heartily recommend.&lt;/i>&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12367</id>
    <title>My Family Heritage</title>
    <updated>2001-12-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" href="/public/fun/animal.jpg"/>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-12-31T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Grandma says that all US Sells are related from the original Sells that came across on the boat after the May Flower. My father pointed out that my boys are not, in fact, the original Sells Brothers (and that we must be related, as the originals have his haircut). </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>My Family Heritage&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Grandma says that all US Sells are related from the original Sells that came across on the boat after the May Flower.&lt;/p>&lt;p align="center">&lt;img border="0" src="/public/fun/animal.jpg" width="500" height="643">&lt;/p>&lt;p>My father pointed out that my boys are not, in fact, the original Sells Brothers (and that we must be related, as the originals have his haircut).&lt;/p>
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12615</id>
    <title>Elvish in the New Age</title>
    <updated>2001-12-29T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-12-29T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>TimT said: od oy dp,ryjomh;olr yjodz [d. dpttu. gomhrtd pm yjr etpmh lrud //yo, SerdarK said: Is that Elfish? ShawnV said: I think it *is* elvish... let me put my laptop in the fire. Ah yes, I can read it clearly now: One Desktop to rule them all, One Desktop to find them One Desktop to bring them all, and in the darkness bind them in the land of Redmond, where the shadows lie Off Topic mailing list </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Elvish in the New Age&lt;/h1>
&lt;H2>TimT said: &lt;/H2>
&lt;P>od oy dp,ryjomh ;olr yjodz&lt;BR>[d. dpttu. gomhrtd pm yjr etpmh lrud&lt;BR>//yo,&lt;/P>
&lt;H2>SerdarK said:&lt;/H2>
&lt;P>Is that Elfish?&lt;/P>
&lt;H2>ShawnV said:&lt;/H2>
&lt;P>I think it *is* elvish... let me put my laptop in the fire. Ah yes, I can read it clearly now:&lt;/P>
&lt;P>&lt;B>One Desktop to rule them all, One Desktop to find them&lt;BR>One Desktop to bring them all, and in the darkness bind them&lt;BR>in the land of Redmond, where the shadows lie&lt;/B>&lt;/P>
&lt;P>&lt;I>Off Topic mailing list&lt;/I>&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12368</id>
    <title>1970s "wocka-wocka" porno guitar</title>
    <updated>2001-12-19T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-12-19T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Sung to &amp;quot;Shaft&amp;quot; by Isaac Hayes &amp;lt; http://www.shaft-themovie.com/soundtrack/track01.mp3 &amp;gt; Who's the man with tongue-in-cheek that's a code machine to all the geeks? (Box!) You're damn right. Who is the man that would replace COM for its brother runtime? (Box!) Can ya dig it? Who's the cat that won't cop out when there's IDispatch all about (Box!) Right on You see this cat Box is a bad mother-- (Shut your mouth) But I'm talkin' about Box (Then we can dig it) He's a complicated man but no one un...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>1970s "wocka-wocka" porno guitar&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;b>&lt;i>Sung to &amp;quot;Shaft&amp;quot; by Isaac Hayes &amp;lt;&lt;a HREF="http://www.shaft-themovie.com/soundtrack/track01.mp3">&lt;font COLOR="#0000ff">&lt;u>http://www.shaft-themovie.com/soundtrack/track01.mp3&lt;/u>&lt;/font>&lt;/a>&amp;gt;&lt;/i>&lt;/b>&lt;/p>&lt;p>Who's the man with tongue-in-cheek&lt;br>that's a code machine to all the geeks?&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Box!)&lt;/p>&lt;p>You're damn right.&lt;br>Who is the man&lt;br>that would replace COM for its brother runtime?&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Box!)&lt;/p>&lt;p>Can ya dig it?&lt;br>Who's the cat that won't cop out&lt;br>when there's IDispatch all about&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Box!)&lt;/p>&lt;p>Right on&lt;br>You see this cat Box is a bad mother--&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Shut your mouth)&lt;/p>&lt;p>But I'm talkin' about Box&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Then we can dig it)&lt;/p>&lt;p>He's a complicated man&lt;br>but no one understands him but his pointers&lt;/p>&lt;p>(Don Box)&lt;/p>&lt;p>&lt;i>John Bristowe&lt;br>Wed &lt;span class="created">12/19/2001 2:02 PM&lt;/span>&lt;br>dotnet discussion &lt;a href="mailto:[DOTNET@DISCUSS.DEVELOP.COM">[DOTNET@DISCUSS.DEVELOP.COM&lt;/a>]&lt;/i>&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12595</id>
    <title>Too Many Secrets</title>
    <updated>2001-12-18T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2001-12-18T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Tue, 12/18/01 During my three years as director of a software project, I learned a lot about people. In fact, I have a little text file entitled "My life as a dog" that may find a home on this site one day. However, because of a thread on the Windows Technical Off Topic list, one of the things I learned came roaring back like a bad acid trip. The #1 problem with any organization is always communication. You can do postmortems on projects all day long and only #2 and above will be a surprise. The problem is ...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Too Many Secrets&lt;/h1>
&lt;P>
            &lt;EM>Tue, &lt;span class="created">12/18/01&lt;/span>&lt;/EM>
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            During my three years as director of a software project, I learned a lot about 
            people. In fact, I have a little text file entitled "My life as a dog" that may 
            find a home on this site one day. However, because of a thread on the &lt;A href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/win_tech_off_topic/message/1718">
                Windows Technical Off Topic&lt;/A> list, one of the things I learned came 
            roaring back like a bad acid trip.
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            The #1 problem with any organization is always communication. You can do 
            postmortems on projects all day long and only #2 and above will be a surprise. 
            The problem is that to build anything of any size, you need a team. As soon as 
            you have to communicate what's in your head to some number of other people, 
            it's going to happen imperfectly. The best way that we've been able to come up 
            with to deal with this issue is hierarchical structures to practice selective 
            information hiding, i.e. exactly the way we build software.
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            However, unlike software, humans have feelings and as soon as they perceive 
            that somebody is hiding something from them, they resent it. Again and again, 
            when I see information withheld to hide "bad" news, those being hidden from 
            know something is up and they get upset. And when they're upset, they send 
            emails and IMs and phone calls around the company looking for every scrap of 
            information they can find, all the while ignoring the work that suddenly seems 
            a waste of time in the face of impending doom. The surprising thing is that 
            when folks are given the truth openly and honestly, no matter how bad it is, 
            they almost always dig in and deal with it. Just knowing that they're trusted 
            with the secrets of the company seems to boost morale.
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            I'm not saying that everyone needs to post their daily activities for everyone 
            to see -- that's too much information. But I am saying that everyone from the 
            CEO on down should be open about the issues they face, including being open to 
            scrutiny and suggestions. I find that after doing that long enough, folks 
            working for me tend to trust me to make the right decisions, leaving them to 
            focus on their own work.
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            The key is that, unlike software systems where components have information 
            hidden from them by their clients, humans can only be effective if they know 
            that the information is available when they want it. Information hiding still 
            needs to happen, but &lt;EM>it's humans that need to choose to hide information from 
                themselves.&lt;/EM> It whole thing falls apart if the managers do the hiding.
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;P>
            </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12596</id>
    <title>Effective C# Available Today</title>
    <updated>2001-12-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2001-12-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Sat, 12/1/01 Effective C# is available now from Addison-Wesley. Of course, it's called Effective Java, but *wow* the overlap is amazing. Some of his items I don't agree with, e.g. return zero-length arrays instead of null (although I see his side) and others have been "fixed" due to advances in C#, e.g. override clone judiciously, but so much of it makes sense in C# (and.NET in general) that it's scary. I feel like asking AW for the text so that I can port it to C# over the weekend. : ) </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Effective C# Available Today&lt;/h1>
&lt;P>
        &lt;/P>
        &lt;p>
            &lt;i>&lt;span class="created">Sat, 12/1/01&lt;/span>&lt;/i>
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p class="MsoPlainText">
            &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0201310058">Effective 
                C# is available now from Addison-Wesley&lt;/a>. Of course, it's called 
            Effective Java, but *wow* the overlap is amazing. Some of his items I don't 
            agree with, e.g. return zero-length arrays instead of null (although I see his 
            side) and others have been "fixed" due to advances in C#, e.g. override clone 
            judiciously, but so much of it makes sense in C# (and .NET in general) that 
            it's scary. I feel like asking AW for the text so that I can port it to C# over 
            the weekend. : )
        &lt;/p>
        </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12369</id>
    <title>I am not making this up...</title>
    <updated>2001-11-27T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-11-27T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>A friend of mine stumbled over this in the Microsoft source code: // Function: RunCommandEx
// Synopsis: runs the given command in the current session, more robust
// than RunCommand
// Arguments: none
// Returns: S_OK if success
// History: October 3, 2000 - created [ name withheld to protect the guilty ]
HRESULT RunCommandEx(LPCWSTR szCmdLine) { DWORD dwTry = 0; HRESULT hResult = S_OK; // try run command 3 times at most while (dwTry That's not quite my definition of robust, but oh well... Tue 11/27/2001 3...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>I am not making this up...&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A friend of mine stumbled over this in the Microsoft source code:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>//  Function:   RunCommandEx
//  Synopsis:   runs the given command in the current session, more robust
//				than RunCommand
//  Arguments:  none
//  Returns:    S_OK if success
//  History:    October 3, 2000 - created [&lt;i>name withheld to protect the guilty&lt;/i>]
HRESULT RunCommandEx(LPCWSTR szCmdLine) {
	DWORD dwTry = 0;
	HRESULT hResult = S_OK;

	// try run command 3 times at most
	while (dwTry&lt;4) {
		hResult = RunCommand(szCmdLine);
		if (hResult!=E_FAIL) {
			// we succeeded
			break;
		}
		dwTry++;
	}
	if (dwTry==4) {
		ATLTRACE(L"COuld start the command even we tried 4 times\n");
		ASSERT(FALSE);
	}
	return hResult;
}&lt;/pre>&lt;p>That's not &lt;i>quite&lt;/i> my definition of robust, but oh well...&lt;/p>&lt;p>&lt;i>Tue &lt;span class="created">11/27/2001 3:52 PM&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12370</id>
    <title>.NET edition of Truckin' (Grateful Dead)</title>
    <updated>2001-11-27T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-11-27T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>&amp;quot;Steal this song right off my page.&amp;quot; You can find it at http://www.ferncrk.com/jittin.html. Use only in well ventilated area. Do not expose to open flame. Stuart Celarier Tue 11/27/2001 3:41 PM </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>.NET edition of Truckin' (Grateful Dead)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Steal this song right off my page.&amp;quot; You can find it at &lt;font COLOR="#0000ff">&lt;a href="http://www.ferncrk.com/jittin.html">&lt;u>http://www.ferncrk.com/jittin.html&lt;/u>&lt;/a>&lt;/font>. Use only in well ventilated area. Do not expose to open flame.&lt;/p>&lt;p>&lt;i>Stuart Celarier&lt;br>
Tue &lt;span class="created">11/27/2001 3:41 PM&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12597</id>
    <title>Thank You, Don Box</title>
    <updated>2001-11-16T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2001-11-16T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Friday, 11/16/01 Last night, in the middle of.NET Band on the Runtime set, Don announced his retirement from DevelopMentor and training. He's sorry to be leaving us, of course, as we are to lose him, but he's excited about doing new things. Running a company gets more consuming as a company gets more successful and Don certainly brought DevelopMentor a great deal of success. And not only did he run his part of the company, but he also brought a amount of rigor and insight to an amazing range of technology t...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Thank You, Don Box&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>
            &lt;i>&lt;span class="created">Friday, 11/16/01&lt;/span>&lt;/i>
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Last night, in the middle of .NET Band on the Runtime set, Don announced his 
            retirement from DevelopMentor and training. He's sorry to be leaving us, of 
            course, as we are to lose him, but he's excited about doing new things. Running 
            a company gets more consuming as a company gets more successful and Don 
            certainly brought DevelopMentor a great deal of success. And not only did he 
            run his part of the company, but he also brought a amount of rigor and insight 
            to an amazing range of technology topics, including C++, COM, DCOM, RPC, XML, 
            Java and .NET, heretofore unprecedented in the training industry. He turned the 
            phrase "them that can't; teach" on its ear. But these are things that are 
            well-known of Don.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            What is perhaps not so well known is the care and dedication that he had for 
            his friends and colleagues. He worked hard to turn his personal success into 
            opportunities for the other technical staff members at DevelopMentor. And he 
            succeeded. He paved the way for people like Ted Pattison, Keith Brown, Tim 
            Ewald, Aaron Skonnard, Martin Gudgin and a host of others who's made a name for 
            themselves in this industry. Of course, I'm also on this list. If you look at 
            the things that I've got listed on this site, i.e. books, articles, courses, 
            conference talks, etc, a staggering amount of it was enabled either directly or 
            indirectly by Don Box. He's an amazing man and it's been an honor and a 
            privilege to work with him these last six years. They're been the richest of my 
            career and of my life. And for that, I'd like to thank him.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Before we get too blubbery, Don has assured the world that he will continue to 
            pursue technology and to communicate it to an eager audience. I, for one, look 
            forward to what he decides to do next. Whatever it is, I'm sure it will be 
            uniquely Don.
        &lt;/p>
        </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12598</id>
    <title>If you knew .NET like I know .NET...</title>
    <updated>2001-11-11T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2001-11-11T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Sun, 11/11/01 Many years ago when Java was new, I dove in. My first program I wrote like a C++ programmer and I didn't get it. Then I rewrote the program as a Java program and it was much nicer, but I still didn't get it. Then I discovered the lack of deterministic finalization and that's all she wrote; my C++ thinking turned me away (the fact that Java was ashamed of my favorite platform and, in fact, all platforms didn't help). Now I've spent the last year doing.NET programming, mostly focused on Managed ...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>If you knew .NET like I know .NET...&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>
            &lt;i>&lt;span class="created">Sun, 11/11/01&lt;/span>&lt;/i>
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Many years ago when Java was new, I dove in. My first program I wrote like a 
            C++ programmer and I didn't get it. Then I rewrote the program as a Java 
            program and it was much nicer, but I still didn't get it. Then I discovered the 
            lack of deterministic finalization and that's all she wrote; my C++ thinking 
            turned me away (the fact that Java was ashamed of my favorite platform and, in 
            fact, all platforms didn't help).
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Now I've spent the last year doing .NET programming, mostly focused on Managed 
            C++ and I didn't get it. I've participated in DevelopMentor's
                ASP.NET and
                Guerrilla .NET and loved both of them, but still didn't get it. I 
            rewrote (with my good friend Jon's help) my entire web site in ASP.NET and 
            didn't get it. And I spent most of last week preparing for my teach of the 
            latest version of DevelopMentor's
                Essential .NET and I *still* didn't get it. Until today. Today I 
            finally got it. The major power of Java wasn't that it was platform 
            independent, as Sun so often touts. The power of Java (and therefore the power 
            of .NET) is that it provides a major productivity boost for the programmer. I 
            realized this today for the first time.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            It started yesterday. Yesterday I ported a tiny little application (&lt;a href="/public/samples/timecli.zip">a 
                time client&lt;/a>) from MFC and C++ to .NET and C#. The first time I ported 
            it, I ported it like it was still C++ and the result was ugly (I was trying to 
            do the standard library trick of representing time as a the number of seconds 
            since some marker time and then translating it into a formatted string at the 
            last moment). In fact, I couldn't even do the nice formatting of the current 
            time since .NET didn't support that means of conversion. But then I remembered 
            that, unlike C++, .NET has proper date, time and span classes. Once I rewrote 
            it in .NET style, it was a thing of beauty. With knowledge of only the name of 
            the sockets namespace (System.Net), I was able to learn .NET and build a time 
            client in under an hour. To paraphrase the closing sentence of &lt;a href="/public/writing/#extapps">
                one of my first articles&lt;/a>, &lt;i>it just makes you want to grab the back the of 
                computer monitor and feel the power of .NET&lt;/i>.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Encouraged by my success and armed with the courage of my convictions (and a 
            couple of &lt;a href="http://www.tlsecurity.net/Textware/Misc/draft-movva-msn-messenger-protocol-00.txt">
                web&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.venkydude.com/articles/msn2.htm">sites&lt;/a>
            given me by &lt;a href="http://staff.develop.com/jasonw/">Jason&lt;/a>
            and &lt;a href="http://www.razorsoft.net/">Peter&lt;/a>), I sat down 
            to write a MSN Instant Messenger application. Those of you unlucky enough to 
            have me as an IM contact saw me log in and log out about a hundred times 
            yesterday (sorry : ). This was because every step of the way, I'd run my client 
            and every step of the way, I'd make more progress. 90% of my code was reading 
            and writing from the sockets and parsing strings. For the former, I used the 
            StreamReader and StreamWriter and for the latter, I used the Regex class. Both 
            did a ton of heavy lifting so I didn't have to. It was amazing.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            But yesterday, I still didn't get it. I was so focused on getting my IM client 
            working (about a half day's work) that I completely missed the magnitude of 
            what I was doing. I was implementing an async notification-based socket 
            protocol after reading an example doc, skimming a spec and digging in. And the 
            code I ended up with wasn't spaghetti. It wasn't production ready yet (my error 
            handling, while present, was rudimentary) and I didn't implement the entire 
            spec, but I had refactored along the way and now I have the beginnings of a 
            nice little namespace for doing IM work. And all of this happened the same day 
            that I first discovered the existence of the System.Net namespace. It's only 
            after reflection (and a good night's sleep) that I finally get it. The power of 
            .NET is the &lt;i>programmer productivity&lt;/i>.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            This productivity comes from a combination of ease of use and flexibility 
            that's going to attract almost everyone. It will attract the VB programmers 
            because of the continued ease of use and the new functionality of the .NET 
            Foundation Classes. It's also going to attract the C++ and the Java programmers 
            for the same reason, but they won't admit that's why they like it. They'll 
            claim to love .NET because of the power and flexibility. Not only are the .NET 
            languages themselves allowed to be fully-featured, but the framework itself has 
            tons of amazing functionality built right in. So much so that it's easy to miss 
            some of it. When I needed to calculate an MD5 hash in my IM client, I went to 
            the net, downloaded some C++ code and built myself a COM object (although I 
            could have easily built a MC++ component, too) and then brought it into my app 
            via interop (see what not being ashamed of the platform can do? : ). That was 
            great, but this morning Peter asked me why I hadn't just used the MD5 
            functionality built into .NET. There's so much stuff in there that I missed it. 
            As a community, we'll be digging into it for a long time to come.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            In the past, I had scoffed at the value of programmer productive over user 
            productivity. My argument was that programmers are soldiers on the field of 
            combat taking bullets and protecting the users at home. This was how I 
            justified the complexity of C++, but measured it against the flexibility of the 
            language and the performance of the produced code, and therefore the pleasure 
            of the user. Don't get me wrong. We're still going to be using C++ for 
            high-performance, shrink-wrap software for some time to come. Windows and 
            Office XQ (or whatever they're going to call them) will still be implemented in 
            C++. Client applications that cannot dictate their deployment environment, i.e. 
            can't dictate the presence of the .NET runtime, will still be implemented in 
            C++ or VB6. Most of the rest is going to be built in .NET without 12-24 months. 
            Stand-alone corporate applications can dictate the presence of the runtime, as 
            can server-side n-tier applications. Web-based applications can take advantage 
            of the compiled and caching performance gains using ASP-style programming, will 
            still enjoying the flexibility and power of ISAPI-style programming via .NET 
            modules and handlers. Everyone in these spaces that works under Windows is 
            going to be moving to .NET, especially the Windows Java programmers who already 
            know the power of such a platform, but want easy access to their DLLs and their 
            COM servers. The reason that people in these environments can now afford to 
            move is that continued research in virtual machine-style environments and 
            increase in machine power has brought about the first platform where &lt;i>ease of use 
                for the programmer does not mean that the user has to suffer&lt;/i>. 
            Applications built with .NET are going to be &lt;i>fast enough&lt;/i> and when it 
            comes to ASP, they're going to be much faster than what we've had in the past.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            The combination of ease of use for the home-by-5 style programmer and the 
            flexibility for the computers-are-my-life style programmer was so great in Java 
            that tens of thousands flooded the Java conferences from the first year. Mix in 
            a user experience that doesn't have to suffer from the programmers' choice of 
            .NET and I finally get it.
        &lt;/p>
        </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12599</id>
    <title>Be Your Own Teddy Bear</title>
    <updated>2001-10-17T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2001-10-17T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Wednesday, 10/17/01 According to legend, the TA office next to the Stanford computer science lab is guarded by a teddy bear. Before a student is allowed to consume valuable time asking a question of the TA, they must first explain it to the teddy bear. Apparently the bear is able to answer 80% of the questions that students ask, saving time for the TAs to play Unreal Tournament. I often feel like I act as the teddy bear for the COM community. I get several email messages a day from folks that consider the m...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Be Your Own Teddy Bear&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>
            &lt;i>&lt;span class="created">Wednesday, 10/17/01&lt;/span>&lt;/i>
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            According to legend, the TA office next to the Stanford computer science lab is 
            guarded by a teddy bear. Before a student is allowed to consume valuable time 
            asking a question of the TA, they must first explain it to the teddy bear. 
            Apparently the bear is able to answer 80% of the questions that students ask, 
            saving time for the TAs to play Unreal Tournament.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            I often feel like I act as the teddy bear for the COM community. I get several 
            email messages a day from folks that consider the &lt;a href="http://discuss.microsoft.com/">
                mailings&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://discuss.develop.com/">lists&lt;/a>
            (resources set up to answer just these kinds of questions) to be too slow, so 
            they ask me directly. If I don't know the answer off of the top of my head, I 
            often respond with the following phrase:
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; "Can you send me a tiny, tiny project that reproduces the 
            problem? --Chris"
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            This, of course, implies that I will actually build and debug the project. And 
            20% of the time, I do. The other 80% of the time, by the time folks have 
            reduced the problem enough to demonstrate it for me, they've already solved it, 
            saving me the time (thank goodness).
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
            Knowing that this is the case, I recommend that you become your own teddy bear. 
            A whiteboard is handy for explaining the problem to yourself and Microsoft 
            development tools are now so handy that you can typically whip out a small 
            reproduction project very quickly. These very activities will often solve the 
            problem, but even if they don't, you've got a concise description of the 
            problem and a small repro case to send to your friends or to post to the list.
        &lt;/p>
        </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12371</id>
    <title>The F-Key Diet</title>
    <updated>2001-10-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
    <published>2001-10-15T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Made you look! (if you don't know what I'm talking about, check here ) </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>The F-Key Diet&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;b>&lt;i>Made you look!&lt;/i> 
&lt;/b> &lt;/p>&lt;p>(if you don't know what I'm talking about, &lt;a href="http://discuss.develop.com/archives/wa.exe?A2=ind0111b&amp;L=dotnet&amp;F=&amp;S=&amp;P=7560">check here&lt;/a>) &lt;/p>
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>