<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed94.atom</id>
  <title>Marquee de Sells</title>
  <updated>2019-08-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
  <link rel="first" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/feed.atom"/>
  <link rel="last" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed178.atom"/>
  <link rel="previous" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed93.atom"/>
  <link rel="next" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed95.atom"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed94.atom"/>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Sells</name>
    <uri>https://csells.github.io/sb6/</uri>
    <email>csells@sellsbrothers.com</email>
  </author>
  <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
  <category term="book" label="Books"/>
  <category term="books" label="Books"/>
  <category term="colophon" label="Colophon"/>
  <category term="conference" label="Conference"/>
  <category term="data" label="Data"/>
  <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
  <category term="interview" label="Interviewing"/>
  <category term="money" label="Money"/>
  <category term="oslofeaturedcontent" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="osloeditorial" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="oslo" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="telerik" label="Telerik"/>
  <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
  <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
  <category term="win8" label="Windows 8"/>
  <category term="writing" label="Writing"/>
  <icon>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/images/vikingme128x128.jpg</logo>
  <subtitle>Chris's insight outlet</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1091</id>
    <title>Dino on Longhorn "Un-programming"</title>
    <updated>2004-02-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-02-05T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Dino's gotten some interesting feedback from his XAML-based articles. Apparently he's hearing from "real programmers" that don't want to "recycle themselves as web designers." This feeling Dino has dubbed "un-programming" and it's the idea that XAML takes away the need to code. XAML is most of what's needed to build trade-show apps, that's true. But look at your apps today: How much of your web app is HTML and how much is C# or VB.NET? How much of your Windows Forms app is in the InitializeComponent method ...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Dino on Longhorn "Un-programming"&lt;/h1>
&lt;P>Dino's gotten some interesting &lt;A href="http://weblogs.asp.net/despos/archive/2004/02/05/67911.aspx">feedback from his XAML-based articles&lt;/A>. Apparently he's hearing from "real programmers" that don't want to "recycle themselves as web designers." This feeling Dino has dubbed "un-programming" and it's the idea that XAML takes away the need to code.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>XAML is most of what's needed to build trade-show apps, that's true. But look at your apps today: How much of your web app is HTML and how much is C# or VB.NET? How much of your Windows Forms app is in the InitializeComponent method and how much is code? While XAML can also be used for general-purpose object creation and initialization, as far as the UI of your app is concerned, all XAML does is replace the HTML or InitializeComponent method. The power of what Avalon can do is separate the UI from the code so that trained designers can work on the specifics of the UI, while real developers work on the specifics of handling events and hooking up the business logic and talking to the back-end datastore.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>I know that as a Microsoft flunky, the value of my reasoning is now suspect. So don't listen to me. &lt;A href="http://weblogs.asp.net/despos/archive/2004/02/05/67911.aspx">Listen to Dino&lt;/A>:&lt;/P>
&lt;P>"XAML is the hot new toy for app developers,&amp;nbsp;and articles inevitably emphasizes that. However, there's &lt;STRONG>life beyond&lt;/STRONG> XAML. And by life here I mean &lt;EM>code&lt;/EM>, managed code, classes, methods, delegates, events and the like.&amp;nbsp;XAML&amp;nbsp;is a shortcut much like ASPX tags in ASP.NET. Believe me, you wouldn't do much with XAML alone and without smart C# or VB.NET code.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>"XAML (and the Longhorn programming style) is not the negation (and let alone the death) of programming."&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1086</id>
    <title>Longhorn Migration &amp; Interop: WinForms &amp; Longhorn</title>
    <updated>2004-02-04T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-02-04T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Karsten wraps up his book, "Developer Guide to Migration and Interoperability in 'Longhorn'", with a chapter on recommendations for preparing to make the best of your Windows Forms code under Longhorn. This chapter includes sample source code.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Longhorn Migration &amp; Interop: WinForms &amp; Longhorn &lt;/h1>
Karsten wraps up his book, &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/Longhorn/understanding/books/migrationguide/default.aspx">"Developer Guide to Migration and Interoperability in 'Longhorn'"&lt;/A>, with &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/Longhorn/understanding/books/migrationguide/default.aspx?pull=/library/en-us/dnlongmig/html/intmiglongch05.asp">a chapter on recommendations for preparing to make the best of your Windows Forms code under Longhorn&lt;/A>. This chapter includes sample source code.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1087</id>
    <title>Getting Started with Your Own Software Company</title>
    <updated>2004-02-04T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2004-02-04T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. Eric Sink talks about starting your own company. More specifically, he recommends that you don't do it unless you're absolutely sure that's what you want to do. Having started several businesses in my time, a couple of things really resonate: "In the business world, ideas are worthless. Real value comes from good execution." and "The developer tools market offers the worst of both worlds. It is a small market, and is occupied by big, powerful competitors." Both are so true. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Getting Started with Your Own Software Company&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/dnsoftware/html/software01262004.asp">Here&lt;/a>. &lt;P>Eric Sink talks about starting your own company. More specifically, he recommends that you don't do it unless you're absolutely sure that's what you want to do. Having started several businesses in my time, a couple of things really resonate:&lt;/P>
&lt;P>"In the business world, ideas are worthless. Real value comes from good execution."&lt;/P>
&lt;P>and&lt;/P>
&lt;P>"The developer tools market offers the worst of both worlds. It is a small market, &lt;B>and&lt;/B> is occupied by big, powerful competitors."&lt;/P>
&lt;P>Both are &lt;STRONG>so&lt;/STRONG> true.&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1084</id>
    <title>Preparing Today for Fewer LH Privileges Tomorrow</title>
    <updated>2004-02-03T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-02-03T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Karsten Jkdjflksjdf (or however you spell his last name : ) pointed out two excellent security articles today. The first is "Developing Software in Visual Studio&amp;nbsp;.NET with Non-Administrative Privileges." Longhorn applications are going to run much better assuming fewer privileges, so getting yourself out of the habit of testing and running your own code as an Administrator is something you can do today to prepare for Longhorn tomorrow. Another excellent article on this topic is from Keith Brown, a Deve...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Preparing Today for Fewer LH Privileges Tomorrow&lt;/h1>
&lt;P>Karsten Jkdjflksjdf (or however you spell his last name : ) pointed out two excellent security articles today. The first is &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/longhorn/default.aspx?pull=/library/en-us/dv_vstechart/html/tchdevelopingsoftwareinvisualstudionetwithnon-administrativeprivileges.asp">"Developing Software in Visual Studio&amp;nbsp;.NET with Non-Administrative Privileges."&lt;/A> Longhorn applications are going to run much better assuming fewer privileges, so getting yourself out of the habit of testing and running your own code as an Administrator is something you can do today to prepare for Longhorn tomorrow.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>Another excellent article on this topic is from Keith Brown, a DevelopMentor colleague and security arch-Nemesis of mine (he never did like my plan of branding "bad" applications by setting the first bit to 1 instead of 0... : ). Item #7 in &lt;A href="http://www.develop.com/kbrown/book/">Keith's online book in progress, A .NET Developer's Guide to Windows Security&lt;/A>, is entitled &lt;A href="http://www.develop.com/kbrown/book/html/howto_runasnonadmin.html">"How to develop code as a non-admin"&lt;/A> and well worth the read for the practical advise as well as Keith's pleasant writing style.&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1083</id>
    <title>"We're full speed ahead on the R&amp;D for speech"</title>
    <updated>2004-02-03T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-02-03T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. Oliver Drobnik&amp;nbsp;extracted a question out of a Q&amp;amp;A session with BillG asking about speech recognition in Longhorn. After BillG makes a very funny comment, he talks about the current state of speech recognition and synthesis today and a bit about the plan for Longhorn. And Oliver? I'd rather not know what you're planning on commanding your computer to do... : ) </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>"We're full speed ahead on the R&amp;D for speech"&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.drobnik.com/oliver/default.aspx?key=2004-02-01T23:34:36.8520576+01:00#comments">Here&lt;/a>. &lt;P>Oliver Drobnik&amp;nbsp;extracted a question out of a Q&amp;amp;A session with BillG asking about speech recognition in Longhorn. After BillG makes a very funny comment, he talks about the current state of speech recognition and synthesis today and a bit about the plan for Longhorn.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>And Oliver? I'd rather not know what you're planning on commanding your computer to do... : )&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1082</id>
    <title>On Behalf of Software Engineers, I'm Sorry</title>
    <updated>2004-02-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-02-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. The one where an hour of phone support with my step-mom causes me to feel embarrassed about what we put normal humans through to use our software.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>On Behalf of Software Engineers, I'm Sorry&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="/12505">Here&lt;/a>. The one where an hour of phone support with my step-mom causes me to feel embarrassed about what we put normal humans through to use our software.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12505</id>
    <title>On Behalf of Software Engineers, I'm Sorry</title>
    <updated>2004-02-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-02-01T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Sunday, February 1st, 2004 I just got off the phone with my step-mother and boy are my arms tired. She way trying to do a mail merge. I told her about a month ago put data into an Excel spreadsheet in a data-like format (and I sent her an example spreadsheet to start from). Then, after entering the data into her spreadsheet, I recommended to her that she choose Mail Merge from the Tools menu in Word and she'd be home free. Of course, she wasn't. For example, after choosing her Excel spreadsheet, she was ask...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>On Behalf of Software Engineers, I'm Sorry&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;i>Sunday, &lt;span class="created">February 1st, 
2004&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I just got off the phone with my step-mother and boy are my arms 
tired. She way trying to do a mail merge. I told her about a month ago put data 
into an Excel spreadsheet in a data-like format (and I sent her an example 
spreadsheet to start from). Then, after entering the data into her spreadsheet, 
I recommended to her that she choose Mail Merge from the Tools menu in Word and 
she'd be home free.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Of course, she wasn't. For example, after choosing her 
Excel spreadsheet, she was asked if she wanted to use first name, Sheet1$, 
Sheet2$ or Sheet3$ as her data. Having zero idea what SheetN$ was, she chose 
something vaguely human-sounding, which was exactly what she didn't want, then 
was frustrated when her data didn't come up. Later, after going away to buy 
hundreds of dollars worth of books (none of them telling her how to do Mail 
Merge using words that she could understand, btw), she opened up her document 
and was presented with a dialog box asking whether it was OK to run an SQL 
statement. &amp;quot;What's SQL?&amp;quot; she asked. &amp;quot;Nothing that any normal human should ever 
have to see,&amp;quot; I replied, growing more embarrassed about the state of the output 
of my industry by the minute.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Later, when we got the data working with the 
merge (Remote Assistance, even over a slow phone line to Fargo, ND, works *very* 
well, once I figured out how to take control of her computer [answer: Take 
Control in the upper left]), she turned her attention to reformatting her 
letter. For example, she'd pasted some text from the web, which, by default, 
left this weird web formatting instead of making it look like the rest of her 
letter, so the styles were very different. Luckily, selecting the text and 
turning off the bold was enough, otherwise I'd have either had to reformat her 
entire letter or talk her through doing it. And how did I tell her to turn off 
the bold? By selecting the text and pressing Ctrl+B? Why did I tell her that? 
Because Word had taken the Bold toolbar icon off the toolbar and I couldn't 
imagine describing to her what the little chevron was for so that she could get 
it back.&lt;/p>&lt;p>I've listed only a small percentage of issues I worked through 
with her, but lest you think otherwise, my step-mom is no idiot. She's a nurse 
anesthetist, so has to keep tons of details in her head all day long or people 
die. Also, she's trained her dogs to win first place obstacle courses in 
competitions around the country, one of whom was said to be untrainable. But 
when it came to Mail Merge, she worked for three weekends straight before giving 
up and calling me. It's clear to me that for anything but the simplest of tasks 
that computers are not even close to ready for normal humans. &lt;b>On behalf of 
the software engineers everywhere, I'd like to apologize to Charlene (my 
step-mom) and the rest of the normal humans everything who are merely trying to 
make computers actually work.&lt;/b> Hopefully Longhorn will fix this problem, but 
until then, I recommended that she return her computer to the manufacturer and 
get herself a Nintendo. After working through this with her for over an hour, I 
was only half kidding.&lt;/p>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/1082">
Discuss&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12506</id>
    <title>What Would You Save If Your House Was On Fire?</title>
    <updated>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="image/jpg" href="/public/spout/bookcoolthumb.JPG"/>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Saturday, January 31, 2004 On a recent thread on my favorite mailing list ever, Jon Kale answers the question &amp;quot;what would you save if your house was on fire,&amp;quot; which triggered my own thoughts along this line. Assuming I've already made sure that the humans and the pets were out of the house, I'd make sure to grab my Omega X-33 (purchased during the bubble, of course), but since I go almost nowhere without it, it's not likely to be burned up w/o its owner. Also assuming I had a set of back-up CDs/DV...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>What Would You Save If Your House Was On Fire?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;i>Saturday, &lt;span class="created">January 
31, 2004&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p>&lt;p>On a recent thread on &lt;a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/win_tech_off_topic">
my favorite mailing list ever&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/win_tech_off_topic/message/25771">
Jon Kale answers the question &amp;quot;what would you save if your house was on fire,&amp;quot;&lt;/a> 
which triggered my own thoughts along this line.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Assuming I've already 
made sure that the humans and the pets were out of the house, I'd make sure to 
grab &lt;a href="http://www.omegawatches.com/omega/co_sp_gents_sub?sublineID=375&amp;lineID=117&amp;sexID=63">
my Omega X-33 &lt;/a>(purchased during the bubble, of course), but since I go 
almost nowhere without it, it's not likely to be burned up w/o its owner.&lt;br>&lt;br>
Also assuming I had a set of back-up CDs/DVDs for the last year in my safety 
deposit box (which I don't have right now... please excuse the pause while I 
purchase a DVD burner... OK, $155 got me &lt;a href="http://www.accupc.com/itemDetail.jsp?pid=DRPIDVR106">
a top-reviewed DVD+R/DVD+RW drive&lt;/a> with 30 blank DVD+RW disks delivered), the 
thing I would most miss is my book collection. The computer books could be 
replaced on demand, but my collection of just-for-fun books has literally taken 
a lifetime to collect and cull down to just things that I really love (click on 
the picture to get a closer look).&lt;/p>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/public/spout/bookcool.jpg">&lt;img border="0" src="/public/spout/bookcoolthumb.JPG" width="528" height="396">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;p>
Often, when I want something comfortable to read, I'll scan the shelves 'til 
something pops out at me and re-read it. Also, when friends &amp;amp; family come to 
town, I often take them to &lt;a href="http://www.powells.com/info/storeinformation.html">
Powell's City of Books&lt;/a> and we play the &amp;quot;Top 5 Books of All Time&amp;quot; game, 
purchasing what they point out for me and writing their name in the book so that 
when I read it, I can talk about it with the recommender (man, I've gotten some &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0375703764/chrissells">
wacky books&lt;/a> that way...). Losing those books, especially the ones I haven't 
gotten to yet, would &lt;i>really&lt;/i> hurt.&lt;/p>&lt;p>On the other hand, because you 
never know when you're going to need to jam, my goal is to fit my entire set of 
positions on a memory hypercube (or whatever). But how do I back up the books 
when the atoms themselves are so satisfying? I mean, how can I recapture the 
feel of my leather-bound &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/068140969X/chrissells">
The Complete Frank Miller Batman&lt;/a>, the back-pocket-worn &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0345337638/chrissells">
The Silicon Mage&lt;/a>, my copy of The Hobbit and The Lord of The Rings signed by 
my mother when I received my Master's Degree because she read them to me when I 
was 10 or the ancient copy of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0517220784/chrissells">
The Complete Sherlock Holmes&lt;/a> given to me by my father and to him by his 
father?&lt;/p>&lt;p>But even if I wanted a lossy digital backup of my books, how do I 
do it? I mean, I can scan all of my books and graphic novels, but only by 
destroying them. Why haven't books, which are produced in digital form, made the 
transition to electronic availability? Are we waiting for the Tablet PC to get 
to a point of ubiquity?&lt;/p>&lt;p>So, in summary:&lt;/p>&lt;ul>&lt;li>How do I back up my 
	favorite atoms?&lt;/li>&lt;li>What would you save if your house was on fire (after 
	humans and pets)?&lt;/li>&lt;/ul>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/1081">
Discuss&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1080</id>
    <title>MarkupCompilation: XAML, BAML, .g.cs Details</title>
    <updated>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Rob Relyea, a Lead PM on the Avalon team, posts some history of XAML as well as a description of how it's compiled into BAML and then into code. He also talks about CAML, which is used today in the PDC bits, but going away in the future. I love these kinds of posts (and these kinds of articles ) because they provide insight into what the designers of a particular technology had in mind, making it so much easier to learn. Having spent years of my life reverse-engineering the intentions of the COM designers o...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>MarkupCompilation: XAML, BAML, .g.cs Details &lt;/h1>
&lt;P>Rob Relyea, a Lead PM on the Avalon team, &lt;A href="http://longhornblogs.com/rrelyea/archive/2004/01/31/2306.aspx">posts some history of XAML as well as a description of how it's compiled into BAML and then into code&lt;/A>. He also talks about CAML, which is used today in the PDC bits, but going away in the future.&lt;/P>
&lt;P>I love these kinds of posts (and &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/longhorn/default.aspx?pull=/library/en-us/dnavalon/html/avalon01062004.asp">these kinds of articles&lt;/A>) because they provide insight into what the designers of a particular technology had in mind, making it &lt;EM>so&lt;/EM> much easier to learn. Having spent &lt;EM>years&lt;/EM> of my life reverse-engineering the intentions of the COM designers out of the header files (because the docs and marketing materials actually pointed us in the wrong direction), it's great when the folks behind the technology spill their guts. Thanks &lt;A href="http://www.simplegeek.com">Chris&lt;/A> and Jeff and &lt;A href="http://longhornblogs.com/rrelyea">Rob&lt;/A>&amp;nbsp;(and &lt;A href="http://anopinion.net/">Mike&lt;/A> and &lt;A href="http://www.gotdotnet.com/team/dbox/default.aspx">Don&lt;/A>&amp;nbsp;and the rest of the MS bloggers).&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1081</id>
    <title>What Would You Save If Your House Was On Fire?</title>
    <updated>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-01-31T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. The one where I spend a peaceful Saturday morning contemplating my life's possessions.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>What Would You Save If Your House Was On Fire?&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="/12506">Here&lt;/a>. The one where I spend a peaceful Saturday morning contemplating my life's possessions.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1076</id>
    <title>U.K. bank sees browserless future</title>
    <updated>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. It's interesting to see an Internet-based company talk about using smart client technologies to provide their customers with a richer experience than they could provide over the web. I roamed the country for years talking to folks about Windows Forms and No-Touch Deployment for their internal stuff and they ate it up. When Whidbey ships and provides ClickOnce capabilities for Windows Forms apps, attaining Internet-reach with smart clients becomes feasible *much* sooner than Longhorn.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>U.K. bank sees browserless future&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://news.com.com/2100-1016_3-5150019.html">Here&lt;/a>. It's interesting to see an Internet-based company talk about using smart client technologies to provide their customers with a richer experience than they could provide over the web. I roamed the country for years talking to folks about Windows Forms and No-Touch Deployment for their internal stuff and they ate it up. When Whidbey ships and provides &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/Longhorn/understanding/pillars/fundamentals/default.aspx?pull=/library/en-us/dnwinforms/html/clickonce.asp">ClickOnce capabilities for Windows Forms apps&lt;/A>, attaining Internet-reach with smart clients becomes feasible *much* sooner than Longhorn.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1078</id>
    <title>MS Blogging About Longhorn 14% of the Time</title>
    <updated>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. Just following up again on When In Doubt, Ignore Longhorn to point out an interesting survey of MS bloggers by David Weller. Apparently, out of 56 recent blog entries by Microsoft&amp;nbsp;employees, 8 were related to Longhorn. That's about 14%, which is a little higher than the 10% that I argued for, but I bet if you took out the ones from me (whose job it is to talk about Longhorn), we'd be closer. : )</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>MS Blogging About Longhorn 14% of the Time&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/dweller/archive/2004/01/30/65351.aspx">Here&lt;/a>. Just following up again on &lt;a href="/12508">When In Doubt, Ignore Longhorn&lt;/A> to point out an interesting survey of MS bloggers by David Weller. Apparently, out of 56 recent blog entries by Microsoft&amp;nbsp;employees, 8 were related to Longhorn. That's about 14%, which is a little higher than the 10% that I argued for, but I bet if you took out the ones from me (whose job it is to talk about Longhorn), we'd be closer. : )</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1079</id>
    <title>Dino on Longhorn Tiles</title>
    <updated>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>The shell-meister himself, Dino Esposito, digs into the one of the most prominent of the new shell features in Longhorn -- the Sidebar -- by showing you how to add your own tile, including how to create the flyout and properties views and how to extend the context menu. Sample code included. Enjoy. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Dino on Longhorn Tiles&lt;/h1>
&lt;P>The shell-meister himself, &lt;A href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/longhorn/?pull=/library/en-us/dnlong/html/lhtiles.asp">Dino Esposito, digs into the one of the most prominent of the new shell features in Longhorn -- the Sidebar&lt;/A> -- by showing you how to add your own tile, including how to create the flyout and properties views and how to extend the context menu. Sample code included. Enjoy.&lt;/P></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12507</id>
    <title>Betting on Longhorn-Only?</title>
    <updated>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Friday, January 30th, 2004 In response to my post yesterday ( When In Doubt, Ignore Longhorn ), Shaun asked whether he should be targeting Longhorn-only right now: [ed: the following has been edited to remove identifying remarks at Shaun's request] Thanks for all the great posts and community participation over the past year. Your recent 'Ignore Longhorn' post alarmed me a bit. I hope that was not born from some aspect of it being pushed past 2006. Anyway, I know you are busy, so I will get to the point. We...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Betting on Longhorn-Only?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;i>Friday, &lt;span class="created">January 30th, 2004&lt;/span>&lt;/i>&lt;/p>&lt;p>In 
response to my post yesterday (&lt;a href="#When_In_Doubt,_Ignore_Longhorn">When In 
Doubt, Ignore Longhorn&lt;/a>), Shaun asked whether he should be targeting 
Longhorn-only right now:&lt;/p>&lt;blockquote>&lt;p>&lt;i>[ed: the following has been edited 
	to remove identifying remarks at Shaun's request]&lt;/i>&lt;/p>&lt;p>Thanks for all 
	the great posts and community participation over the past year. Your recent 
	'Ignore Longhorn' post alarmed me a bit. I hope that was not born from some 
	aspect of it being pushed past 2006.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Anyway, I know you are busy, so I 
	will get to the point. We are mid-sized, established s/w company, and a 
	Microsoft shop to the core (SQL Server, Analysis Services, VB, we embed VBA 
	etc...). I am facing a huge decision regarding building our next gen app 
	architecture. We need to ship in 1H 2006, and (IMO) we need to target rich 
	and reach, so Longhorn is on my list of possible directions along with some 
	ASP.NET 2.0 / ClickOnce combination. &lt;/p>&lt;p>I am enjoying working with 
	Longhorn (XAML in particular), but I'm having a hard time shaking the 
	feeling that I am taking too much of a gamble if I go Longhorn-Only, but 
	some of the aspects are just so compelling. On the other hand, I'd hate to 
	make a huge 2-3 year dev investment in ASP.NET only to ship something in 
	2006 that is not revolutionary/differentiated. I firmly believe our existing 
	3 million lines of solid COM code has plenty of life in it too.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Any 
	insight or advice you might have would be greatly appreciated. I know it is 
	probably difficult without understanding our company or market, but maybe 
	some general advice to someone who is targeting a 2006 release. I guess my 
	other worry surrounds the Longhorn adoption rate, but obviously none of us 
	can predict that!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>&lt;p>Here was my answer:&lt;/p>&lt;blockquote>&lt;p>
	Shaun, if you think that Longhorn is going to help you build a 
	differentiated product that'll help you be more successful, then great! 
	That's why we're building it.&lt;/p>&lt;p>On the other hand, if I were you, I 
	wouldn't put all my money into a single investment. Instead, I'd use some 
	diversification strategies like you would with your financial portfolio. At 
	this point, the ship date of Longhorn, along with the list of features it 
	will support when it ships, is merely speculative. I won't put more than 10% 
	of my available investment time/money/staff into it, leaving the rest of my 
	portfolio for getting the most I can from my existing and/or near future 
	technologies.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Specifically, you ask about ASP.NET 2.0 and Windows 
	Forms/ClickOnce. Both of those technologies rock. ASP.NET is going to be &lt;i>
	the&lt;/i> way to build web sites and services for the next decade at least, 
	even after Longhorn's been out for years, since it has the reach across our 
	existing OSes and competing OSes. Plus, ASP.NET 2.0 has a dizzying list of 
	new features that people will spend years just taking full advantage of. For 
	reach, you can't make a better investment than ASP.NET.&lt;/p>&lt;p>For rich, on 
	the other hand, Windows Forms + ClickOnce is a killer combo. The updated 
	Windows Forms in Whidbey along provides some amazing new capabilities, not 
	the least of which is the new GridView, which you can read about in &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/columns/winforms.asp">
	Michael's new Wonders of Windows Forms piece&lt;/a>. Also, look for &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/msdnmag/">
	a &amp;quot;What's New in Whidbey Windows Forms&amp;quot; piece in MSDN Magazine&lt;/a> RSN. 
	ClickOnce (which you can learn more about in &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/Longhorn/understanding/pillars/fundamentals/default.aspx?pull=/library/en-us/dnwinforms/html/clickonce.asp">
	Duncan's ClickOnce piece&lt;/a> and in &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/msdntv/episode.aspx?xml=episodes/en/20040108ClickOnceJC/manifest.xml">
	Jamie's ClickOnce talk&lt;/a>) is &lt;i>the&lt;/i> way to deploy rich clients in 
	Whidbey &lt;i>and&lt;/i> in Longhorn, so digging into that technology is a very 
	good idea.&lt;/p>&lt;p>As time goes on and Longhorn becomes a more solid 
	development investment, you should put more of your portfolio into it. If 
	you've got plenty of time/money/staff, than 10% now could mean an entire 
	pilot project in Longhorn, which would be a good thing. But if you've got 
	limited amounts of time/money/staff that you really need to yield a dividend 
	now, Longhorn is dangerous for you and should only be something you dabble 
	with at this point.&lt;/p>&lt;p>For you specifically, a mid-sized company, you 
	should carve off a chunk of your dev. staff to build a pilot in Longhorn. 
	This lets you dabble while the rest of your staff is busy with existing and 
	near future technologies. And as you dabble and &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/longhorn/community/newsgroups/">
	notice things that don't work at all as you expect or need, let us know&lt;/a>! 
	Operators are standing by to take your calls! We're at a stage in our 
	development process where we're able to give &lt;i>much&lt;/i> more attention to 
	the fundamentals than we will be at beta, so the 10% you put into Longhorn 
	now could yield large dividends in the future.&lt;/p>&lt;p>And as to your follow 
	up comment, I'm happy that you enjoyed my response, but I'm pretty sure an 
	autograph from Sting would be cooler. : )&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
	</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/1077</id>
    <title>Betting on Longhorn-Only?</title>
    <updated>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2004-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. The one where I address some specifics about what amout of effort you should be putting into Longhorn right now.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Betting on Longhorn-Only?&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="/12507">Here&lt;/a>. The one where I address some specifics about what amout of effort you should be putting into Longhorn right now.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>