<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed148.atom</id>
  <title>Marquee de Sells</title>
  <updated>2019-08-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
  <link rel="first" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/feed.atom"/>
  <link rel="last" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed178.atom"/>
  <link rel="previous" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed147.atom"/>
  <link rel="next" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed149.atom"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://csells.github.io/sb6/subfeeds/feed148.atom"/>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Sells</name>
    <uri>https://csells.github.io/sb6/</uri>
    <email>csells@sellsbrothers.com</email>
  </author>
  <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
  <category term="book" label="Books"/>
  <category term="books" label="Books"/>
  <category term="colophon" label="Colophon"/>
  <category term="conference" label="Conference"/>
  <category term="data" label="Data"/>
  <category term="fun" label="Fun"/>
  <category term="interview" label="Interviewing"/>
  <category term="money" label="Money"/>
  <category term="oslofeaturedcontent" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="osloeditorial" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="oslo" label="Oslo"/>
  <category term="telerik" label="Telerik"/>
  <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
  <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
  <category term="win8" label="Windows 8"/>
  <category term="writing" label="Writing"/>
  <icon>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://csells.github.io/sb6//public/images/vikingme128x128.jpg</logo>
  <subtitle>Chris's insight outlet</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/356</id>
    <title>Current Project Command Prompt for VS.NET</title>
    <updated>2002-12-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-12T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. Another answer from the VS.NET Info Center Q&amp;A Forum describing how to start a command prompt and the file explorer in the directory of the current project.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Current Project Command Prompt for VS.NET&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://searchvb.techtarget.com/vsnetATEAnswers/0,293820,sid8_gci862641_tax292095,00.html">Here&lt;/a>. Another answer from the VS.NET Info Center Q&amp;A Forum describing how to start a command prompt and the file explorer in the directory of the current project.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/353</id>
    <title>ADO.NET -- Offline and On Tap</title>
    <updated>2002-12-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
    <published>2002-12-12T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "In the.NET* Framework, rich clients can bring database servers to their knees, just like Web-based applications. But with the disconnected nature of ADO.NET, your rich clients can manipulate and analyze database data without impacting the database server. Once you have the data in the rich client, you can do high-performance analysis of the data—including sorting, filtering, and querying—without expensive server calls. In this article we will show you how to use DataSet, DataView, and XmlDataDocument...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>ADO.NET -- Offline and On Tap&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://cedar.intel.com/cgi-bin/ids.dll/content/content.jsp?cntKey=Generic%20Editorial::net_bottleneck&amp;cntType=IDS_EDITORIAL&amp;catCode=BZW">Here&lt;/a>. "In the .NET* Framework, rich clients can bring database servers to their knees, just like Web-based applications. But with the disconnected nature of ADO.NET, your rich clients can manipulate and analyze database data without impacting the database server. Once you have the data in the rich client, you can do high-performance analysis of the data—including sorting, filtering, and querying—without expensive server calls. In this article we will show you how to use DataSet, DataView, and XmlDataDocument to make your rich clients work with database data in a disconnected way."</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/351</id>
    <title>Team Leader</title>
    <updated>2002-12-11T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2002-12-11T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>From Assaf Levi: </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Team Leader&lt;/h1>
From Assaf Levi: </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/12568</id>
    <title>Of Eggs and Omelets</title>
    <updated>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="spout" label="The Spout"/>
    <published>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>My life has been one long series of experiments. I tried to be a know-it-all jerk in high school and found that this tended to cut into my social life (drastically), so I stopped (or am still stopping, depending on how well you know me : ). I tried to be a &amp;quot;ground floor&amp;quot; employee for a small company, but that stopped being fun when the repetition and bureaucracy hit and it became clear that any profits that might someday happen would be kept at the owner level. I tried being an employee for a larg...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Of Eggs and Omelets&lt;/h1>

        &lt;p>My life has been one long series of experiments. I tried to be a 
        know-it-all jerk in high school and found that this tended to cut into 
        my social life (drastically), so I stopped (or am still stopping, 
        depending on how well you know me : ). I tried to be a &amp;quot;ground floor&amp;quot; 
        employee for a small company, but that stopped being fun when the 
        repetition and bureaucracy hit and it became clear that any profits that 
        might someday happen would be kept at the owner level. I tried being an 
        employee for a large company, but when my projects started getting axed 
        based on political winds that, as a low-level grunt, I had no control 
        over, I went looking elsewhere. Then I found DevelopMentor. The 
        combination of working on lots of different things with lots of smart 
        people was something that I loved more than anything I've since found.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>But even that didn't stop my experimentation. After teaching and 
        consulting for a while, I decided that instead of just talking about 
        building software, that I would take one of my ideas and build a 
        software development team. There I worked to build the best software 
        development team that I've ever had the pleasure to work with and a 
        learned a *ton* along the way. However, the fact that the product itself 
        was a commercial failure didn't make for lasting employment.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>So, late last year, I started another whole series of experiments, 
        this time aimed at making myself solvent as an independent in a down 
        economy. I've been doing all kinds of crazy things to see if I could use 
        them to help build my brand, my business and my customer base. Some of 
        them have been critically acclaimed and a few have even been 
        commercially viable, at least to the point that I can continue to pay my 
        mortgage (many of my friends weren't so lucky). I have been successful 
        in that I've gotten to do a lot of cool things and work with a lot of 
        smart people.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>However, what I've found is that to remain independent, I have to 
        spend a lot more time doing promotion and marketing, which goes against 
        every fiber in my being. The problem is, although I've experimented a 
        bunch, especially as related to this year's DevCons, I don't have any 
        natural marketing aptitude and I don't know where to turn for help. So, 
        I fall back on my old standby -- experimentation.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>Over several years, I've experimented with several sales/marketing/PR 
        folks and organizations and so far, haven't found what I'm looking for 
        as far as &amp;quot;mentors&amp;quot; go (to be fair, my standard for comparison includes 
        Don Box, Tim Ewald and John Robbins, so I'm not surprised I haven't 
        found someone to meet that bar). Even if I did meet that person, or may 
        have already met him/her, I don't know that I'd recognize it. I just 
        have no standard for comparison. With software, it either works or it 
        doesn't. With marketing, did it succeed or fail because of the quality 
        of the product or the quality of the marketing? The whole thing is too 
        damn squishy and it drives me nuts!&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>My most recent set of experiments is to let a friend of mine, a 
        long-time marketing guy that I've known for years, run rough-shod over 
        my newsletter subscribers, asking them all kinds of questions and for 
        their help in various ways, offering my money and my time as incentives. 
        Will it work? I have no idea. Is it risky? You bet. I've lost a dozen or 
        more subscribers and who knows what some people think of me now that 
        I've let marketing ideas into what I do (and I'd like to apologize again 
        to the folks that I drove away or offended in this most recent 
        campaign). Is it worth the risk? Yes it is, but not for the promised 
        return (I still think my marketing friend was on happy pills the day he 
        quoted his marketing targets). What makes it worth the risk is that I've 
        identified a weakness in myself and I'm willing to perform the 
        experiment and make the mistakes to see if I can come out better on the 
        other side. Even if I fail, I've learned something. Eventually, I'll get 
        that omelet made, no matter how many eggs need breaking.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>And to those of you who suffer with me through my experiments, thank 
        you very much. You have no idea how much you mean to me.&lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
        &lt;a href="/350">
		Discuss&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
        </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/350</id>
    <title>Of Eggs and Omelets</title>
    <updated>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. In which Chris describes his most recent personal journey on the path to true enlightenment. : )</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Of Eggs and Omelets&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="/12568">Here&lt;/a>. In which Chris describes his most recent personal journey on the path to true enlightenment. : )</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/347</id>
    <title>Info.NET, similar to Dashboard on MSN 8</title>
    <updated>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. From Ryan Dawson: I had talked earlier in the week to Chris about an application I was developing, and I said I would post it as a news item when it was finsihed (I should say just started, I am not close to being finished). If you are interested in advancing this program, please contact me -rd933@msn.com.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Info.NET, similar to Dashboard on MSN 8&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.codeproject.com/useritems/infodotnet.asp">Here&lt;/a>. From Ryan Dawson: I had talked earlier in the week to Chris about an application I was developing, and I said I would post it as a news item when it was finsihed (I should say just started, I am not close to being finished).  If you are interested in advancing this program, please contact me -rd933@msn.com.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/346</id>
    <title>.NET Passport Manager Source Licensing Program</title>
    <updated>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. From Spencer Harbar: The.NET Passport Manager Source Licensing Program enables developers and other interested individuals to access and use Passport Manager Source code for both commercial and noncommercial purposes, including the creation and distribution of derivatives of the licensed source code for non-Windows applications. Licensees are free to use the source code also to develop, debug, and support their own commercial software for integration with.NET Passport. Passport Manager Source code is ...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>.NET Passport Manager Source Licensing Program&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/dnpport/html/passptma.asp">Here&lt;/a>. From Spencer Harbar: The .NET Passport Manager Source Licensing Program enables developers and other interested individuals to access and use Passport Manager Source code for both commercial and noncommercial purposes, including the creation and distribution of derivatives of the licensed source code for non-Windows applications. Licensees are free to use the source code also to develop, debug, and support their own commercial software for integration with .NET Passport. Passport Manager Source code is available for installation with any version of .NET Passport.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/343</id>
    <title>Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft .NET</title>
    <updated>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. From John Bristowe: "Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft.NET is the released and supported version of the Web Services Development Kit Technology Preview (WSDK)."</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft .NET&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/webservices/building/wse/">Here&lt;/a>. From John Bristowe: "Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft .NET is the released and supported version of the Web Services Development Kit Technology Preview (WSDK)."</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/342</id>
    <title>Web Services Enhancements for .NET</title>
    <updated>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft.NET (WSE) provides advanced Web services functionality for Microsoft Visual Studio.NET and Microsoft.NET Framework developers to support the latest Web services capabilities. Enterprise ready applications can be developed quickly with the support of security features such as digital signature and encryption, message routing capabilities, and the ability to include message attachments that are not serialized into XML. Functionality is based on the WS-Securit...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Web Services Enhancements for .NET&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/webservices/building/wse/default.aspx">Here&lt;/a>. "Web Services Enhancements 1.0 for Microsoft .NET (WSE) provides advanced Web services functionality for Microsoft Visual Studio .NET and Microsoft .NET Framework developers to support the latest Web services capabilities. Enterprise ready applications can be developed quickly with the support of security features such as digital signature and encryption, message routing capabilities, and the ability to include message attachments that are not serialized into XML. Functionality is based on the WS-Security, WS-Routing, WS-Attachments and DIME specifications."

In their own wonderful way, Microsoft has changed the name yet again to the set of classes that they've put together to do heavy-duty web services stuff. It was GXA, then WSDK and now it is, finally and officially, the Web Services Enhancements (WSE). If you liked it with the old names, you'll love it with the new name. : )</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/345</id>
    <title>Mono Runs ASP.NET</title>
    <updated>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. From Jesse Ezell: Ximian released mono 0.17 today: "Many new features as well as plenty of bug fixes. Many new System.Data providers and a more mature System.Web (ASP.NET) which can now be hosted in any web server. A simple test web server to host asp.net has been released as well."</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Mono Runs ASP.NET&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.go-mono.com">Here&lt;/a>. From Jesse Ezell: Ximian released mono 0.17 today:

"Many new features as well as plenty of bug fixes. Many new System.Data providers and a more mature System.Web (ASP.NET) which can now be hosted in any web server. A simple test web server to host asp.net has been released as well."</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/344</id>
    <title>Visual Studio Tools for Office</title>
    <updated>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2002-12-09T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "Businesses and developers have long benefited from the ability to use Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) to customize Microsoft Office applications and integrate them with existing data and systems. While VBA continues to be an important part of Office development (and benefits from the new features of 'Office 11,' the next release of Office), 'Visual Studio Tools for Office' will provide significant advances in the areas of language choice and innovation, security, deployment, and the integrated de...</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Visual Studio Tools for Office&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio/techinfo/officetools/default.asp">Here&lt;/a>. "Businesses and developers have long benefited from the ability to use Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) to customize Microsoft Office applications and integrate them with existing data and systems. While VBA continues to be an important part of Office development (and benefits from the new features of 'Office 11,' the next release of Office), 'Visual Studio Tools for Office' will provide significant advances in the areas of language choice and innovation, security, deployment, and the integrated development environment (IDE)."

I once heard that most VB programmers are actually office programmers, so keeping them happy was *way* more important than keeping the average VB programmer happy, let alone a lowly C programmer. So, until .NET is ubiquitous and there's a seamless porting tool, looks like VBA and VSA will co-exist in Office instead of just having VSA replace VBA in a single version. This is goodness, imo.</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/341</id>
    <title>More PetShop 2.0 Fun</title>
    <updated>2002-12-08T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2002-12-08T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "Carl and Mark discuss the PetShop 2.0 application which Vertigo developed as an answer to Sun's PetShop J2EE benchmark application. The.NET version proves to be at least 2 times as fast as the J2EE version."</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>More PetShop 2.0 Fun&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.franklins.net/dotnetrocks.asp">Here&lt;/a>. "Carl and Mark discuss the PetShop 2.0 application which Vertigo developed as an answer to Sun's PetShop J2EE benchmark application. The .NET version proves to be at least 2 times as fast as the J2EE version."</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/340</id>
    <title>WinForms Control Inspector -- Spy++ for .NET</title>
    <updated>2002-12-07T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term="tools" label="Tools"/>
    <published>2002-12-07T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "ControlInspector hooks on to all events on a given control, user-control or form and shows when they are fired, along with any eventargs. It even handles custom events and custom event args using dynamically generated assemblies." This looks *very* cool and was inspired by DevelopMentor's Guerrilla.NET course. Wahoo!</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>WinForms Control Inspector -- Spy++ for .NET&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.codeproject.com/useritems/controlinspector.asp">Here&lt;/a>. "ControlInspector hooks on to all events on a given control, user-control or form and shows when they are fired, along with any eventargs. It even handles custom events and custom event args using dynamically generated assemblies."

This looks *very* cool and was inspired by DevelopMentor's Guerrilla .NET course. Wahoo!</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/338</id>
    <title>Browse Rotor source code online</title>
    <updated>2002-12-03T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-12-03T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "When I started looking at the source code for rotor, I couldn’t believe how invaluable it was. I also wanted to have an easy way of viewing classes in the files. So I wrote this little utility to help me out, to find common namespaces, classes, delegates, enums, etc in the source files." This is an online browsable resource for digging into the source for a lot of the CLR base class library. Fabulous! [JasonW or SamG -- it's hard to know]</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>Browse Rotor source code online&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.123aspx.com/rotor/default.aspx">Here&lt;/a>. "When I started looking at the source code for rotor, I couldn’t believe how invaluable it was. I also wanted to have an easy way of viewing classes in the files. So I wrote this little utility to help me out, to find common namespaces, classes, delegates, enums, etc in the source files."

This is an online browsable resource for digging into the source for a lot of the CLR base class library. Fabulous!

[JasonW or SamG -- it's hard to know]</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://csells.github.io/sb6/337</id>
    <title>.NET Rocks Interviews Chris Sells</title>
    <updated>2002-11-29T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <category term=".net" label=".NET"/>
    <published>2002-11-29T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <summary>Here. "Chris talks with Carl and Mark about COM and.NET components, finalizers, disposing, Smart Client Windows Forms Applications (we still don't know what to call these things), how to navigate sellsbrothers.com, interview weed-out questions, and why he calls it Sells Brothers. Also, Chris finally clears up the age-old question of why C++ programmers feel so superior to mere humans."</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1>.NET Rocks Interviews Chris Sells&lt;/h1>
&lt;a href="http://www.franklins.net/dotnetrocks.asp">Here&lt;/a>. "Chris talks with Carl and Mark about COM and .NET components, finalizers, disposing, Smart Client Windows Forms Applications (we still don't know what to call these things), how to navigate sellsbrothers.com, interview weed-out questions, and why he calls it Sells Brothers. Also, Chris finally clears up the age-old question of why C++ programmers feel so superior to mere humans."</content>
  </entry>
</feed>